Greetings and welcome to an LGR computer thing
大家好，欢迎来看LGR攒电脑节目
that’s a smidge more modern than usual.
本期节目与往期相比有点现代
'Cause yeah, today we are putting together a brand new workstation / editing rig using
因为呢，今天我们要攒一个全新的视频工作站
all these lovely parts here, among other things.
用这些耐人的部件，还有其他的部件
Ahh, this is always exciting, we’re gonna be going over the parts I chose, dismantling
啊~组装新机永远是令人兴奋的，我们将欣赏部件，拆掉
my old build, putting together this brand new one, setting everything up with Windows,
我的老机器，然后装配个新的，装上Windows并配置好
and then putting it through its paces with a few select programs.
然后用些程序测试这台新工作站
Yeah, upgrading my work PC is something I do every four or five years or so, with my
是啊，我每四五年都要升级我的工作站
last build being back in early 2016.
我的老机器是2016年上半年攒的
I didn’t do a video on that, but it was this machine right here,
那个我没录视频，但机器就在这里
what I called my mini-fridge monolith.
我把它叫做“小冰箱电脑”
I’m actually gonna be using this exact same case for today’s build and just swapping
我这回也用这个机箱，只是把里面的
out all the internals, ‘cause I don't know, I’m still quite fond of it.
部件都换新，因为我......我反正喜欢这样
It’s a Fractal Design Define XL R2, one I chose not only for its brushed steel industrial
机箱型号Fractal Design Define XL R2，我不光是因为这个
kitchen aesthetic, but because I was actively seeking
拉丝的工业化厨房设计而用它，而且我也是一直在找
something with a ton of space that’s super quiet.
这种又大又不吵的机箱
It’s got these giant, slow-moving fans on the front, the back, the bottom, a huge BeQuiet
这个机箱的上下和后面都有一个超大的，转速慢的风扇
CPU cooler installed, and tons of room for everything I wanted for parts and cable management.
里面用BeQuiet的CPU散热器，而且还有很多空间理线
And what I’ve had in here since 2016 was an Intel i7-6700 CPU, 64 gigs of DDR4-3000
我从2016来一直在用这个 Intel i7-6700 CPU，64G DDR4-3000MHz 内存
RAM, a couple of M.2 drives, a couple SSDs, and an Nvidia GeForce GTX 1080 Ti.
两个M.2设备，两个SSD，还有一个 Nvidia GeForce GTX 1080 Ti
Linus:So Nvidia, FXXK YOU!
Oh and an old Avermedia capture card, which I’ve been meaning to upgrade for years but
还有一个老式Avermedia采集卡，我想升级已有多年
it does the job so whatever.
但是一直能用，所以就那样了
And yeah, I mean, all this stuff works fine still.
当然，这些部件工作良好
But only just fine, because my workflow has changed quite a bit since 2016.
当然也就算工作良好，因为我的工作流程自从2016以来改变了许多
I’ve used Adobe Premiere since forever, so that’s nothing new.
我一直都用Premiere，所以这个没啥可说的
But I’ve also started using After Effects more for things like my intro and text graphics,
但我也在用AE搞些开幕动画或者字体特效之类
as well as a bunch of filters and plugins that really bog things down.
还有各种超级麻烦的过滤器和插件之类
Not to mention I’ve upgraded cameras three times since then, with my current one being
更不必说在那时之后我已经升级了三回相机了，现在我用的是
a Lumix GH5S recording at 4K 60fps and 150 megabits per second.
这台Lumix GH5S，能录4K，每秒60帧，每秒能产生18.75MB数据
注：原文150Mbps 1Mbps = 125kbps
And ah, yeah, all that combined has slowed things down a lot while editing, even with
当然，这匹老马处理这些素材可谓极慢了，
proxies, and render times have gone through the roof.
就算开了代理剪辑也是一样的慢:-(
预计还剩5小时38分钟
注：代理剪辑是将素材压缩以好剪辑。软件诸如Adobe Media Encoder
So that’s why I decided to go all out this time and grab a buncha stuff that’s admittedly
这就是为什么我出去买来这些东西
unjustifiable if it weren’t for my job.
要不是为了工作，我才不会升级的
The centerpiece being this insane processor here, the AMD Ryzen Threadripper 3970X.
注：发布于2019-11 京东报价￥15299
当然，核心部件是这个超级无敌的AMD YES锐龙系列线程撕裂者3970X
I’ve been setting aside cash for it ever since I saw what it could do when it launched
2019年末发布之时我就震惊了，早已为此预备好钱了
in late 2019, and then when I got my tax refund this year I just decided to take the plunge.
然后当我拿到今年退税之后，我就狠心购买了
This thing alone cost two thirds of what my entire previous PC cost,
这个性能怪兽占了我上回攒机花销的三分之二
and again, if it wasn’t a business expense I would not be able to justify it.
再说一遍，如果不是为了工作我是不会买这个的
32 cores, 64 threads, 144 megs combined cache.
32核，64线程，共计144MB缓存
注： 3MB 一级缓存 + 16MB 二级缓存 + 128MB 三级缓存
Yeah just complete nonsense that’s really all about getting me a smoother time editing
这简直是疯了！这样的话，我在剪辑渲染时
and rendering, this is not a gaming build or anything like that.
绝对更加流畅，而且这台机器不是为了玩游戏的
Not to say it can’t game, I’m sure it’d do just fine in that regard.
不是说这个玩不了游戏，我认为这个电脑玩起游戏来会很流畅
But if I was building a new gaming PC I’d go with an i9-9900KS
但是要是玩游戏的话，我就用i9-9900KS了
注：京东原价￥4699 八核十六线程 16M三级缓存
or something with fewer cores.
或者核心更少的CPU
In fact, I’ve got an Intel-based PC in my living room that I use exclusively for playing
实际上，我起居室里玩游戏的电脑就是Intel的CPU
games, that’s a whole ‘nother rig that doesn’t do any work and is just built for gaming.
这台电脑我平常不用它工作，只是用来玩游戏
This is all about the work, and to that effect, I’ve also chosen a motherboard that seems
这个工作站只为快速工作设计，为此，我特意选择了
like it’ll do what I need: an MSI Creator TRX40.
一个能满足我工作需求的主板：微星 Creator TRX40
注：京东报价￥7777
I’ve gone with Gigabyte boards for the longest time, but I’ve been impressed with the MSI
我一直都是用技嘉的主板，但我游戏电脑用的
board I have in my gaming PC and figured I’d give one of their sTRX4 models a try.
微星主板给我印象很深，而且我想用用这个sTRX4型号
It’s got a crapload of ports and overclocking features and things I’ll never use.
这个有超级多的接口，超频支持，还有好多我用不到的特性
The sound chip for instance, I don’t use on-board sound at all, it’s all external
至于声卡呢，目前我不用板载的
solutions for me and work these days.
现在我都用外置的声卡来工作
Currently a Mackie Big Knob Studio for both recording and playback, it works well for
注：该录音工作台淘宝报价￥3300左右
目前我用这个Mackie Big Knob Studio监听控制器来录音回放
my mics that needs XLR phantom power and uh.
这个和我需要幻路供电（麦克风供电方式之一）的麦克风工作良好。而且呢
I like the big knob.
这大旋钮真耐人:-)
Anyway yeah, moving onto the memory situation, and I’m going with my longtime preference
好的，现在来看看内存。我这回还用海盗船的
Corsair, this time 128 gigabytes of their Vengeance LPX DDR4-3600 CL18 RAM.
这回是海盗船复仇者LPX DDR4 3600MHz CL18内存
注：中关村参考报价一条￥1199，这个是一盒四条！
Should be a tad faster than what I had before, and of course it’s twice the amount.
应该比我之前有的要快，当然这个也是之前容量的两倍
Believe it or not, I do push 45, 50 gigabytes of memory used in certain projects, sometimes
实际上，我处理一个项目时经常要用45-50GB内存
even more with really big videos like the E3 one I did a while back,
甚至在非常长的视频上用得更多，诸如上回去E3的视频（机翻熟肉：av61962940）
so the extra headroom will be nice.
那么这些额外的空间就很好了:-)
Speaking of which, I also really wanted to boost my storage speed, so I went with three
说到这个，我还想提升存储速度，所以我买来这三个
of these Samsung 970 EVO Plus M.2 NVMe sticks, which should be stupidly fast.
三星 970 EVO Plus M.2接口 NVMe SSD，这个应该非常快了
注：1T版京东原价一根￥2199，2T版京东原价一根￥4999
Even more so than the 950 Pros I had in my last build, and those were already quite quick,
甚至比我上回我用的950 Pro SSD容量还要多，当然那些已经很快了
注：现已停产，512GB版中关村参考报价￥2699
just far lower in capacity.
只是容量太少
These are two, one, and one terabyte, so I’ll be using the two for my main video assets,
这是两个1T的，一个2T的，所以我用这个2T的作为剪视频的主力
one for proxies and screen captures, and the other one for the operating system and application files.
这一个作为代理剪辑和录屏的存储，另一个作为系统和应用存储盘
I’ve got another 4 terabyte SSD already that I’ll keep as well, but it’s a lot
当然，这个4T的SSD我也将保留好
slower so it’ll likely be for overflow of things
但是这个更慢，所以这个就用来
that haven’t been moved onto my network storage.
把还没迁移到NAS里的东西给暂时保存起来
Yeah that’s other stuff, there’s about 128 terabytes both here and off-site that
是啊，这就是另一个玩意了，这上下都有128TB的存储空间
I used for storage and backups.
一般用于存储和备份用途
Continuing with these parts though and my search for silence.
接下来就是我对电脑安静的探索了
I went with another BeQuiet CPU cooler since I was so happy with the last one I had, this
我这回又用上了BeQuiet（德商必酷），因为上一个这个很好用
one being the Dark Rock Pro TR4.
这个型号是BeQuiet Dark Rock Pro TR4
注：京东原价￥699
I don’t wanna do liquid cooling or have any audible pumps or motors or loud fans,
我不太想用水冷或者听见很吵的泵，马达或是风扇
so these huge coolers of theirs are fantastic.
所以他们生产的散热器超级好的！
Just a couple of enormous, slow-moving fans and a monstrous heatsink that’s about as big as your head.
只有两个转速慢的超大风扇和与你头差不多大的散热片
In terms of power, I’m going with -- well this is actually my old power supply but it’s
至于电源呢，我将要用这个......这个实际上是我的老电源
still awesome so I’m keeping it.
但是这个还能用，我就留下来了
It’s an EVGA Supernova thousand watt power supply, one of their 80 plus platinum ones
这是个 EVGA Supernova 一千瓦电源, 他们 80 plus platinum 系列之一
for whatever that’s worth.
这就很值
It’s served me well for years now, never left me hanging on power needs, and it’s
这玩意一直工作良好，从来没有让我在电源方面折腾
got all modular connections and it’s super quiet, so yeah, it makes the cut.
它是全模块设计，而且超级安静，所以这个还能满足我的要求。
Lastly there’s the video card, this EVGA RTX 2080 Super FTW3 whatever the heck.
最后是显卡，这个 EVGA GeForce RTX 2080 SUPER FTW3 什么玩意的
注：游戏性能比官版差劲一点，制作时已下架，太平洋电脑网参考报价￥6499
Not the best card in existence for gaming, but again, it’s not a gaming build so it’ll
不是最好的游戏显卡，但是再说一遍，这不是游戏电脑
do the job with its 8 gigs of video memory and such.
Less than the 11 gigs I had before, but it’s still faster overall, supports RTX, and I
这个显存比上一个11GB的少了，但是总体更快，支持光追
didn’t see the need to shell out for a Ti or a Titan on this rig.
而且我也没必要为此买一个Ti系列或者是TITAN系列的显卡
I’m holding out for the 3080 before going whole hog on a new GPU, and even then that’ll
我在买这个GPU前一直等待3080上市，但是那个
be dropping into my living room PC and not this one, so the 2080 Super works fine.
我更乐意用在我客厅里的游戏电脑，而不是这个，所以这个就很好了
Oh and uh, yeah 64-bit Windows 10 Pro, I guess there’s that too.
当然，还有这个64位的 Windows 10 专业版，我觉得这个也上个镜吧
注：官网售价¥1817，仅限企业购买:-(
缓慢撕开以看见密钥
Nothing exciting there but there it is.
没有什么特别的
Right! So that’s it for the parts, I am more than ready to put this thing together.
好的，介绍到此为止。我已经准备好装机了
But first, let’s take the old one apart real quick,
但是首先呢，我要快速地拆下旧部件
and start assembling all this Threadripper goodness!
然后开始组装这堆线程撕裂者之类的吧
Alrighty so, first order of business is getting my 2016 build disassembled,
好的，首先我要把这些在2016攒的部件拆下来
at least most of the way.
至少是大部分
As discussed, I’m gonna be keeping the power supply
我刚才提到，我要保留这个电源
and one of the 2.5” SSDs installed in the new machine,
其中一个2.5吋的SSD要装在新机器里
and the video capture card will be sticking around as well for the time being.
这个视频采集卡也暂且保留在新配置中
Same goes for all the 120 and 140 millimeter case fans,
还有这个120mm和140mm机箱风扇
along with the blu-ray burner I have in there.
和机箱里的蓝光刻录机
Which uh, heh, come to think of it
这个嘛，反正想想
I’ve never once used for burning or even reading blu-rays.
我从未用来刻过一张蓝光，甚至读过一张:-(
But I like having it on-hand for all the older optical media that I’m constantly reading
但我还是想留着以用来读取我经常要用的老光盘（CD或者DVD）
and writing for other LGR projects.
并且用来为其他LGR项目刻盘
Here’s one part that won’t be sticking around though, this older Sandisk Ultra 3D SSD.
这里还有一个我不会留下的部件，这个老闪迪Ultra 3D SSD
I think this one’s only 250 gigs and it’s quite a bit slower than the others, so yeah,
我觉得这个250G太小而且相比其他简直太慢，所以呢
it’s better suited to an old laptop or something.
这个最好还是用在老笔记本之类的吧
Then there’s the 4 terabyte SSD that I will be keeping installed.
然后我还要保留这个4TB SSD
Even though its read/write speeds are slower than the M.2 sticks, it’s still nice to
尽管这个读写速度都要比M.2的慢，但是这用来
have the additional local storage for lesser-used files.
备份本地不经常用的文件还是很有用的
I really dig Fractal Design’s removable drive trays by the way, just one of the many
顺便说一句，我确实喜欢Fractal Design的可移动硬盘托
things I love in this case.
这仅仅这个机箱耐人之处之一:-)
That and the fact that it’s so wide open inside, making it super easy to reach all
实际上，这个机箱空间超大，能让我十分容易地
the screws on the motherboard, something I can’t say for most of my previous ATX cases.
够到主板的每一个螺丝，这个在之前的ATX机箱里是难以办到的
Seems like there’s always some weird metal doohickey in the way of one little screw or
好像那种机箱总有一些奇怪的部件会挡住我的螺丝刀
another, or large CPU coolers would bump up against the sides but nope, not here!
或者超大CPU散热器会撞到侧面，但是这个没有:-D
Anyway that’s that.
无论如何就是这样啦！
The motherboard is outta there, along with all the rest, so let’s move onto the new stuff!
新主板就在这里，带着这一堆军师谋臣，那么咱们就赶紧让他们各就位吧
Starting with the MSI motherboard and its ridiculous number of quirks and features.
先从这个超级多功能的MSI主板开始说
This is one appealing design, I gotta say.
这个主板的设计不得不说，超级不错的！
Those eight RAM slots bring to mind heftier server boards, I quite like it.
这八个内存插槽让我想起了十分强大的服务器主板，我十分喜欢
And it’s not too far off the deep end of “try-hard gamer boi” aesthetic either, thankfully.
当然庆幸的是，这个设计也没有偏离“努力玩家”的美学。
努力游玩，保持安静
Though it does have some RGB nonsense happening on the I/O panel,
尽管接口那里也有些烦人的RGB之类的东西
a crystal-looking thing they call “The Mystic Light.”
他们称其为“魔幻之光”的水晶样东西
Eh it’s fine, I can turn it off if it’s bothersome.
额，这烦人的玩意我就关掉好了
I just prefer minimal or no RGB lighting and purposely avoid
我只是喜欢少量的RGB或者干脆没有
things like glowing memory modules and LED fans.
当然，我也不喜欢发光内存条或者LED风扇之类的
I swear, half the builds I see online these days are lit up like the Vegas Strip on acid,
我承认，现在我在网上看见的装机视频，开机后简直就像在新葡京赌场嗑药一样
I don’t get it.
反正我就是不明白
Ah well, enough old man being old, let’s see what else is in here.
唉，我都这把年纪了......再看看这里有啥
注：LGR出生于1986年，真名Clint Basigner
We got a bag full of drive cables and things, nothing I need since I already have everything
这里有一包驱动器连接线之类的东西，我不太需要
in there from the last rig.
因为我上个机器都有
There’s also this impressive-looking wi-fi antenna, again not needed since c’mon now,
这里还有些吸引人的Wi-Fi天线，当然我也不想要因为呢
10 gig ethernet is where it’s at.
得了吧，家里有万兆网为嘛不用呢:-|
And then there’s this PCI Express card, one of the more intriguing inclusions with this board.
这里还有一个PCI-E卡，在这些附赠品里算是比较有趣的了
MSI calls this the M.2 Xpander Aero Gen4, an unappealing mouthful of a name, but a highly
MSI称其为M.2 Xpander Aero Gen4，一个十分绕口的不吸引人的名字
注：条上的字：这个扩充卡最高支持PCIe 4.0带宽，而传输速度或被处理器和芯片组限制
useful card that takes the mainboard’s M.2 slots from 3 to 7.
但是这个十分有用，因为这个可以将主板上的M.2接口从3个扩充到7个
Yeah, this whole top part of the card comes off letting you insert 4 more M.2 SSDs.
是啊，这整张卡的顶部可以让你再插入四个M.2接口的SSD
Awesome for any future expansion!
对于未来升级相当有好处:-)
But seeing as I only have 3 of them right now, let’s set the card aside and go ahead
但鉴于我只有三个M.2 SSD，这张卡就先放在一边吧
and get these installed on the motherboard itself.
先把这三个SSD装在主板上
The way this works on the TRX40 is that you have two metal heatsink bars screwed on there.
在这张主板上安装SSD呢，你会看见这里拧着俩金属散热片
Removing them provides access to the M.2 slots,
拧掉它们，你会看见M.2插槽
complete with thermal pads covered in blue protective film.
上面盖着用蓝色保护膜覆盖的导热垫
Pretty dang fancy compared to what I’ve had before, I’ve only ever had a couple
与之前的主板相比，这简直是太好了
slots out in the open with no built-in heat dissipation at all.
之前的就俩开放的插槽，而且没有内置散热机制
So yeah, just gonna remove the blue film on the thermal pads, slot each of the three modules
所以呢，仅需把最上面的蓝色保护膜去掉，把三个SSD插进去
into place, and screw those heatsink plates on top of them to keep everything down.
然后把散热片拧在这仨上面，保证安装到位
Nice.
o(￣▽￣)ｄ
Should keep things a bit cooler,
应该能让这些东西保持凉爽吧
and it also just looks snazzy as crap all tucked away like that.
而且鉴于把这些都塞进去了，整块板更加整洁了
With that outta the way it’s time to whip out the Threadripper, and man, this is some
废话少说，咱们赶紧把线程撕裂者给打开。天啊，这个包装
excessive packaging, to say the least.
不得不说，有点过度了
Honestly it looks more like a plasma rifle power cell or some sci-fi macguffin than it does a CPU holder.
说真的，这玩意与其说是CPU盒子，更像是等离子枪的电池或是没用的高科技产品
What are you even supposed to do with it afterwards, set it on a shelf, just empty?
你难道还要把这空盒子在架子上给供奉起来吗？
Extraneous packaging aside though, this is truly a gorgeous bit of hardware.
抛开这个超大包装，这个CPU简直是怪兽级别的
Kinda reminds me of the Pentium Pro in terms of how oversized the processor is, what a
这个让我想到了Pentium Pro，都是超大个的CPU
mesmerizing piece of high tech art.
真是令人着迷的高科技杰作
It also came with a big ol’ watercooling mount,
这个还附带着一个超大水冷固定架
as well as this Threadripper-branded screwdriver.
还有撕裂者牌的螺丝刀
The latter is used to unlock this metal socket covering, so you can remove the plastic pin
后者是用来拧掉金属CPU槽罩子的，然后你就可以
shields and get to the uh, sliding insertion thingy.
移除塑料保护罩，进而将CPU滑入槽中
Heh, yeah this is new to me man, check this out.
好吧，这个对我来说是头一回，那么来看看吧
The whole CPU, orange plastic and everything, slides right down into this little cradle
这整个CPU，包括桔色塑料之类的，全都滑入这个小支架中
and clicks down into place over the pins.
并将其向下弯，使其与与针脚位固定对齐
Then you screw it all back in there so it connects, and it is now good to go!
然后上好螺丝，使其连接，就装好了
Sure have come a long way from ZIF sockets.
当然，这个和零插拔力插槽简直是相差甚远
Next up is the RAM since it goes underneath the CPU cooler, and since I’ve got four
下一步是装内存，鉴于散热器会覆盖部分插槽
identical modules, they’ll go in these four slots spaced apart from one another in order
而且这四条内存是一样的，它们就插在最两侧的四个插槽中
for optimal quad-channel support.
以获得最佳的四通道内存支持
Then we’re ready for the Dark Rock Pro cooler
然后我们就开始安装散热器了
in all its comically-sized copper aluminum glory.
这个超级大的铜铝金属块
Pretty sure I’ve seen smaller children actually.
确实应该和小朋友的头差不多大
And hey neat, it came with its own screwdriver.
这个也附带一个螺丝刀，那就更好了
A pretty nice one too from the feel of it.
摸上去相当不错
First step here is to screw in these metal brackets and plastic standoffs around the
首先是将金属和塑料支架固定在
socket itself, which is where the heatsink will screw into here soon.
CPU插槽周围，也就是一会固定散热器的地方
And it actually came with some generic thermal paste in the box, but I’m gonna use some
而且这个实际上附带了一些普通的硅脂，但是我还是想用些
of my trusty ol’ Arctic MX-4 instead.
我长期信赖的Arctic MX-4
注：4g装淘宝售价￥29
How much do I use?
用多少呢？
Enough, that’s how much.
这些应该够了
Got that slathered on the Threadripper, and now we can just plop down the whole cooler
在将CPU涂上厚厚一层后，我们就可以在顶部放下散热器
on top, place the metal bracket in between, and screw that down through two holes in the top of the heatsink.
在两侧将金属托架固定好，然后通过上面的两个洞，上好螺丝
Sure glad it came with that screwdriver, otherwise I don’t know if I had any that were long
幸亏它们附赠了一个螺丝刀，要不然我不知道我有没有
and skinny enough to get down in there.
能够到如此深的螺丝刀
Lastly, there’s a 135mm fan that goes in the middle of the heatsink assembly.
最后，在散热片的中间还需要放一个135毫米的风扇
That clips right into place with these little metal brackets and gets plugged into the CPU
这个正好能用金属支架卡在里面，然后与另一个
fan header on the motherboard right alongside the other fan so they’re both able to be
风扇同时插在主板上的风扇接头，这样的话
controlled at once.
它们就可以同时被控制了
Alrighty, things are moving quickly at this point!
好了，剩下的事情就很好解决了
Just gonna get everything we’ve done so far dropped into the case and screwed into
把我们刚攒好的东西都放进机箱里，然后将其
the existing standoffs, conveniently they’re all the same as last time.
固定在机箱支架上，幸亏上螺丝的位置与上回的一样
And I’ll start connecting some of the power cables for the motherboard, CPU power, and the case fans.
然后我就要给主板，CPU和风扇接电线了
As well as the SATA drive cables, USB ports, and all the different front panel connections.
当然还要给SATA驱动线，USB接口和其他前面板的东西接线
At this point the expansion cards are about all that’s left, with the graphics first
在这时基本上就剩下扩展卡了，我要先处理这个
on the agenda since it’s so large.
显卡，因为这玩意忒大了
And yeah, these RTX cards are monstrous, taking up three PCI brackets around back.
当然，这个显卡十分的大，占据了后面三个PCI挡板位
It still seems crazy to me when cards take up two slots, three is just hilarious.
对我而言，占领两个就相当不得了了，而三个更是不可想象
Now, normally I’d install the GPU into the first PCI Express slot, but ah.
一般来说，我都把显卡插在第一个PCIe插槽中，但是现在这个
Yeah, doing that would completely cover up the chipset fan on the motherboard, something
会盖上主板上的芯片散热风扇，这种事
I’d rather avoid if I can.
我一般都尽量避免
So I’m gonna install it a couple slots down so it sits below the fan.
所以我这回得降低两个槽放，这样就会在风扇下面了
Not exactly ideal I suppose, but it’ll work since each slot is PCIe 4.0 x16 anyway, and
跟我想的不太一样，但是每个插槽都是 PCIe 4.0 x16 标准的
I only have one more card to install.
而且我就再装一张卡
That being the old Avermedia Game Broadcaster HD,
这张老 Avermedia Game Broadcaster HD视频采集卡
which I use to capture old PC footage below 1080p.
我一般用它在低于全高清分辨率下捕获旧电脑录像
It’s just a tiny little thing, slots in there no problem.
就是这个小玩意，插进去应该没啥问题
And yeah, that’s about it!
好啦，基本上就是这样啦!
Other than spending a while tidying things up and generally taking care of cable management,
然后再花点时间整理一下里面，再理理线
the only thing left to do will be installing Windows and setting up all my software.
最后就是安装好Windows，再把软件都设置好
Check it out!
来看看！
The new LGR Threadripper workstation is lookin’ mighty fine indeed.
全新LGR线程撕裂者工作站看上去超级的好
I’m gonna assume I didn’t miss anything stupid and get the side panels put back on there.
应该不会落下嘛没干的，而且侧面板也装好了
Then hook everything back up, power it on, and see what happens!
再把所以东西都固定好，然后开机看看吧!
Ahh, the sweet sound of nothing!
啊~安静的感觉真好
It can be hard to tell if it’s turned on at all audibly,
基本上很难听见啥噪音
just the way I like it since I record so much in this room.
正如我经常在这个屋子里的感觉一样
And yeah, once it’s tested out all the components and memory and stuff, we reach the MSI BIOS.
当然，在主板侦测到所有组件和存储之后，我们就看见了MSI BIOS
Success!
(*^▽^*)
Everything seems to be plugged in and working as intended, so that’s a good sign.
看上去所有部件都已插入并良好工作，这是个好信号
And dang there sure is an extravagant amount of junk to look at and tweak in here, which
这里有好多的选项来围观或是更改
is one reason I wanted another MSI board.
这也是为啥我想再用微星的主板
I particularly like the Board Explorer screen, where you can mouseover and see each and every
我尤其喜欢“主板概览”功能，你可以通过鼠标看见主板上正在使用的
component, cable, add-on card, and peripheral that’s currently active on the PC.
基本部件啊，线缆啊，扩展卡啊，还有外围设备
I mean, I guess you could just look down and see for yourself, but whatever, this amuses
当然，你也可以拆开电脑自己看，但是呢
me and I enjoy its existence.
我对此十分高兴，这个玩意真是实用
After this, it’s Windows setup time!
在此之后，就该安装Windows了
And yeah yeah, Windows 10 setup, blah blah it is what is.
Errr，这个安装程序嘛，估计都融化在各位每一滴血里了:-P
After a few minutes it’s all done.
几分钟后就装好了
The only thing that needed to be manually set up was my capture card, but otherwise
安装后唯一需要我干预的是采集卡
it’s back to business as usual.
但是其他的东西开机即用，一如往常
So let’s test some crap out!
那么现在咱就搞点事情吧
I mean, just look at all those threads
你看看，这些线程
64 threads across 32 cores, resulting in about
32核心64线程，这样导致了
128 times my previous level of arousal, mmm.
我的唤起程度比之前要高128倍，嗯~（怀疑开车，有更好翻译请弹幕覆盖）
Naturally the first thing I had to try was SkiFree for Windows 3.1.
自然地我第一个要测试的是Windows 3.1的SkiFree
Oh yeah, smooth as silk even in ultrawide.
是啊，无尽雪原上的丝滑感受:-P
It’s barely even taxing the CPU at all, what a beast!
再看CPU，基本没有载荷，多么厉害啊B-)
Yeah okay, enough joking around.
好啦，好啦，咱们不玩啦
So the actual first thing I tried was Duke Nukem 3D Atomic Edition from 1996.
实际上我测试的第一件事是1996年发行的Duke Nukem 3D Atomic Edition
Amazingly, it runs flawlessly in DOSBox, with hardly a skipped frame or a hint of slowdown!
令人震惊的是，这玩意在DOSBox里丝滑运行，没有跳帧或是一丝卡顿:-\
The Ryzen Threadripper is truly the future.
线程撕裂者就是未来啊
All right for real now though, let’s go for Premiere Pro.
好了，热身结束，咱来上Premiere！
One of the biggest reasons I wanted the upgrade was to improve rendering times, and here’s
我想要升级的主要原因之一是提升渲染时间
some footage of the previous 6700K machine encoding a typical 12 minute LGR video with
这里是我之前用6700K渲染的一个通常的12分钟
all the settings and stuff I normally use.
LGR纪录片素材，所有设置都是我的常用设定
On there it took over an hour to finish rendering that particular video.
老机器花了超过一个小时来渲染这个视频
And that was one of the better scenarios,
而这还算是比较好的成绩了
some of my longer videos took three or four hours.
有些长的视频要花三四个小时来渲染
Now let’s try it out on the new PC, same exact file, settings, all that.
现在咱们用新机器，还用老文件，老设定之类的
We know it’ll be faster, but by how much?
当然新的更快，但是能快多少呢？
A lot!
快到不知道哪里去了:-)
Yeah it only took 25 minutes to finish rendering the project,
新机器只花了25分钟就渲染完了这个项目！
using identical plugins and export settings as before.
用着和以前一样的插件和输出设定
Ahh, fantastic, that’s seriously like a weight lifted off my shoulders right there.
啊~这简直是给我省了太多的忙啦！
And yeah, that’s about it for the new work PC!
那么呢，这就是我全新的视频工作站啦！
Even knowing what kinda numbers I’d be getting beforehand, having looked at endless tests
尽管之前都知道我将要用这个跑出什么成绩
and benchmarks online, it’s still somewhat mind-boggling to see for myself what this
在网上我都看见了好多好多的测评资料
setup can do with my own video projects.
但当我看见它在渲染视频时的表现时我还是难以置信
Including this very video you’re watching, this entire thing was edited and rendered in record time using the new rig,
包括您所看到的这个视频，整个都是在新机器上剪辑渲染的
and it was a buttery smooth experience the whole way through.
整个过程都是超级流畅的
As you’d hope for how much it cost, jeez, imagine if it sucked.
当你想到这一整套要烧多少钱时，天哪，您还是别问了吧
Thankfully it doesn’t though, and I’ve used some of the extra time to enjoy a few
幸亏没人问（要不然割肉疼啊），而且我还花了一些业余时间享受了
maps of Doom Eternal, and appreciate how well it makes use of all
几局Doom永恒，而且我为其能
those processor threads. What a bonkers thing.
多么高效地利用如此多的核心而惊呆。真是令人疯狂！
当你仅仅是为了展示所有的64个逻辑核心
而需要这垂直的监视器的话
I know some games will require disabling a number of cores or they won’t run, something
我知道有些游戏不禁止核心就跑不起来，幸亏
the included MSI software makes pretty simple, thankfully.
微星主板软件有简洁的方式配置
But so far, all the games I’ve tried have worked great without having to disable or
但是目前为止，我玩过的所有游戏都运行得挺好
tweak anything, it’s all been rock solid.
没有让我再折腾，一切都是十分可靠的
Yeah, even though it’s a work PC it’s still been undeniably fun messing around with
是啊，尽管这是台工作站，但不可否认的是，玩起游戏来还是相当有趣的
games just to see what it can do.
就为了看看这台电脑的能力
And hey, if it’s in this video, that means it’s technically work right?
再说呢，要是我给剪进去的话，那就意味着这些都工作得好呗
Oh yeah for sure, this is definitely work.
那自然是啊，它们工作都非常良好
Doom, Wreckfest, Red Dead Redemption 2, Minecraft RTX,
新版毁灭战士啊，撞车嘉年华啊，荒野大镖客2啊，光追版Minecraft啊
I say they’re all sort of kinda work at this particular moment in time.
这些要我说，至少在现在都运行得还可以
Doing YouTube as a job is bizarre.
反正做Youtuber是有点奇怪
本视频由SuperBart翻译，原作者LGR上传于2020年5月15日
Speaking of which, I hope you enjoyed this video!
说到这里呢，我希望大家看得愉快
I know it’s not my usual fare but I tried making it enjoyable regardless.
虽然这不是我的老本行，但是我还是尽力让这个视频有趣
Do check out some more LGR if ya like this kinda thing.
你要喜欢这些的话，一定要关注我做的其他视频
Especially if you’re into retro computing, I post new videos each week.
尤其是复古电脑爱好者，我每周都会在油管投视频的
And as always, thank you very much for watching!
最后，一如既往，感谢大家收看！